我们的下一个原则是每个变量都有一个目的。
Our next principle is having one purpose for each variable.
在这个一年中的一天的例子中，参数dayOfMonth
In this day of year example, the parameter dayOfMonth
用来计算一个非常不同的值。
is to be used to compute a very different value.
它被重用来计算回报
It's reused to compute the return
函数的值，它不是一个月中的某一天。
value of the function, which is not the day of the month.
不要重用参数，也不要重用变量。
Don't reuse parameters, and don't reuse variables.
变量不是编程中的稀缺资源。
Variables are not a scarce resource in programming.
你应该自由地介绍他们。
You should introduce them freely.
你应该给他们起个好名字。
You should give them good names.
当你不再需要它们的时候就停止使用它们。
And then just stop using them when you stop needing them.
如果一个变量
You will confuse your reader if a variable that
过去的意思是一件事突然开始有意义
used to mean one thing suddenly starts meaning something
不同的几行下来。
different a few lines down.
这不仅是一个容易理解的问题，
Not only is this an ease of understanding question,
但它也会影响软件的安全性和改变的准备。
but it also affects safety from bugs and readiness for change.
方法参数尤其应该
Method parameters in particular should generally
保持原样。
be left unmodified.
这对于做好改变的准备非常重要，
This is very important for being ready for change,
因为在未来，方法的另一部分
because in the future, some other part of the method
可能想知道原始参数
may want to know what the original parameters
方法是。
and method were.
你不应该在计算的时候把它们吹走
You shouldn't blow them away while you're computing
方法的主体。
the body of the method.
所以用final作为方法参数是个好主意
So it's a good idea to use final for method parameters
以及尽可能多的其他变量。
and for as many other variables as you can.
最后一个关键字，记住，表示变量
The final keyword, remember, says that the variable
不应该被重新分配。
should never be reassigned.
Java编译器将静态地检查它。
And the Java compiler will check that statically.
下面是我们的第二个臭例子。
Now, here's our second smelly example.
在一年中的某一天的方法中实际上有一个潜在的错误。
There was actually a latent bug in that day of year method.
它根本不能应付闰年。
It didn't handle leap years at all.
作为解决这个问题的一部分，假设我们编写一个闰年方法。
As part of fixing that, suppose we write a leap year method.
这就是它，一种叫做leap的方法。
Here's what it is, a method called leap.
它需要一个代表年份的整数
It takes an integer representing the year
然后返回true或false，具体取决于
and then returns true or false, depending on
不管那一年是不是闰年。
whether that year is a leap year or not.
这是尸体。
And here is the body of that.
这里有很多臭代码。
And there's lots of smelly code in here.
实际上在这段代码中隐藏了一些错误。
And there are actually bugs hidden in this code.
它有什么缺陷，我们有什么风格问题
What bugs does it have, and what style problems that we've
已经谈过了？
already talked about?
让我们在下面的练习中看看。
Let's see in the exercises next.